. . . One for All and All for Fun!
The Three Musketeers is a action, adventure,
romance film directed by Richard Lester.
In 17th century France, young D'Artagnan wants to join the King's Musketeers, but instead befriends three legendary musketeers—Athos, Porthos, and Aramis—and
together, they become embroiled in the political intrigue surrounding King Louis XIII and his adversaries, particularly the powerful Cardinal Richelieu.
D'Artagnan, played by Michael York.
Athos, played by Oliver Reed.
Aramis, played by Richard Chamberlain.
Porthos / O'Reilly, played by Frank Finlay.
Lady de Winter, played by Faye Dunaway.
Constance de Bonancieux, played by Raquel Welch.
The Three Musketeers (also known as The Three Musketeers (The Queen's Diamonds)) is a
1973 swashbuckler film based on the 1844 novel by Alexandre Dumas.
It is directed by Richard Lester from a screenplay by George
MacDonald Fraser, and produced by Ilya Salkind.
It stars Michael York, Oliver Reed, Frank Finlay, and Richard Chamberlain as the musketeers, with Raquel Welch, Geraldine Chaplin,
Jean-Pierre Cassel, Charlton Heston, Faye Dunaway, Christopher Lee, Simon Ward, Georges Wilson and Spike Milligan.
The film adheres closely to the novel, and also injects a fair amount of humor.
It was proposed in the 1960s as a vehicle for The Beatles, whom
Lester had directed in A Hard Day's Night and Help!
It was shot by David Watkin, with an eye for period
detail, in Madrid and Segovia, Spain.
The fight scenes were choreographed by master swordsman William Hobbs.
The musical score was composed by Michel Legrand.
The Three Musketeers premiered in France on 11 December 1973.
It was both a critical and commercial success and was
nominated for several awards, including five BAFTAs.
Raquel Welch won a Golden Globe for her performance.
The Four Musketeers, a sequel shot back-to-back with its
predecessor, was released the following year.
The film explores themes of france, paris, france,
based on novel or book, swordplay, fight.
The tone is emotional.